本字幕由YYeTs人人影視原創翻譯製作 最新最快的美劇 請登陸
www.YYeTs.net
本片字幕翻譯製作：   Pc
一天
再見   夥計們
Bye, guys.
三年了
It's three years.
在一起三年了
Three years together.
小夥子們
The lads.
我和你?
Me and you?
我們會再見面的 真的嗎?
We'll see each other again. Really?
他們不會...
They're not going, are they?
抱抱!
Group hug!
再見  女士們!  回頭見
See you, ladies! See you later.
抱抱
Group hug.
哦  哇  哇  哇!
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Tilly? - Tilly ?
- Callum!  - Callum !
Tilly 是時候回家了
Tilly, come on.It's time to go home.
來吧 Callum !
Come on. Callum!
我們沒有真正見過面
You know, we've never actually met.
事實上 我們見面好幾次了
Actually, we have. Several times.
有嗎?
Have we?
你闖到我的生日聚會  把我叫成 Julie
You gatecrashed my birthday party, called me Julie,
還把紅葡萄酒灑到我的頭上
and spilled red wine down my top.
哎喲
Ouch.
好吧  我對此深感抱歉
Well, I'm sorry about that.
不  你一點都沒有
No, not at all.
你是最開心的那個
You were delightful.
是嗎?
Was I?
不  不  你沒有
No. No, you weren't.
如果你不是 Julie  那...
Look, if you're not Julie, then...
-我是 Emma  -Emma
-I'm Emma.  -Emma.
Emma Morley Emma Morley.
好吧 我送你回家
Listen, I'll walk you home.
這就是我
So this is me.
歡迎回家
Shh!Welcome home.
所以辯論是好的 但任何人都可以談...
So debate is fine,but anyone can talk...
只是有時候 更需要的是行動
Just sometimes,action's what's needed.
改變這個世界 我完全同意
To change the world. I completely agree.
那麼當你40歲的時候 你想幹什麼?
So what are you gonna be when you're, I don't know, 40?
四十?
Forty?
我能說著名的嗎? 超有錢?
Can I say famous? Horribly rich?
太可怕了 你是真是奢侈得可怕
Terrible. You're so terribly posh.
你要去哪裏?
Where are you going?
我只是要去 刷刷牙
I'm just gonna go brush my teeth.
你知道   剛纔又吸菸又喝酒的...
You know, booze and fags and...
我不介意
I don't mind.
我介意
I do.
好吧  很快
Listen, won't be a minute.
我離開的時候 你不要那個哦
No playing with yourself while I'm gone.
什麼?
What?
好  集中精力
All right, concentrate.
集中精力 不要搞砸這件事!
Concentrate. Do not cock this up!
你要閃了?
Oh, you're going?
嗯  天黑了 所以我想我可以...
Well, it's getting light out, so I thought I could just...
你走吧 如果你想要走的話
You should go if you want to go.
這真是太諷刺太辛酸了
It's very poignant. Very bittersweet.
真的   我只是想你可能想睡了
Really I just thought you might wanna get some sleep.
我不一定要走
I don't have to go.
不  不 走吧 我並不擔心
No, no, go. I'm not bothered.
閃人吧
Sneak off.
我不是想溜走
I wasn't sneaking off.
- 跳出窗口  沒關係
-Jump out the window for all I care.
雖然這是五樓
It's five floors up, mind.
好吧  我會留下來 好嗎?
Look, I'll stay. All right?
我會留下來
I'll stay.
來吧
Come on.
對不起  我不擅長此道
Sorry, I'm no good at this.
只是每當我跟別人上牀睡覺
It's just whenever I go to bed with someone,
最後要不就是大笑 要不就大哭
I always end up either laughing or weeping,
其實介於兩者之間也不錯
and it could be nice to go for something in between.
瞧  這很好
Look, that's fine.
是啊 也許我們 可能只能當朋友
That's fine. Maybe we could just be friends.
好吧 朋友
Okay. Friends.
你知道今天是聖斯威遜節嗎?
Of course, you know it's Saint Swithin's Day today, don't you?
什麼?
What is?
今天 聖斯威遜節  7月15日
Well, today. Saint Swithin's Day, the 15th of July.
你怎麼知道的?
How do you know that?
他被安葬在溫徹斯特大教堂
Well, he was buried in Winchester Cathedral,
就是我上學的地方
which is where I went to school.
那麼  LA - DEE - DA
Well, la-dee-da.
La-dee-da La-dee-da.
你知道嗎 有一首詩是這樣的
You know, there's a poem.
"如果在聖斯威遜節 下雨
"If on Saint Swithin's Day, it doth rain
" 什麼  什麼  什麼 依然存在"
"something, something, something remain."
Dexter  真有詩意
Dexter, that's beautiful.
閉嘴
Shut up.
讓我們睡個安穩覺
Let's get some sleep.
但是  Dex
But, Dex.
如果不下雨...
If it doesn't rain...
...你想要做些什麼嗎?  就我和你
...do you want to do something? Me and you?
-你沒事吧?  -擡起來  擡起來
- Are you all right? - Lift, lift.
好  好  我來
Okay, well, I'm coming up.
難道你能叫人來搬這東西嗎?
Couldn't you have just hired someone to move this stuff?
不
No.
如果是我的話  我會叫人幫忙
Look, I would have paid.
好的  從你那邊擡起來
All right,lift from your end.
顯然  你已經從來沒有做過
You've obviously never done
在你的生活了一天的工作
a day's work in your life.
說真的  EM 我的航班在四個小時後就要飛走了
Look, seriously, Em, my plane leaves in four hours.
這就更加要你來搬了
All right, well, all the more reason why you should lift.
天吶
God's sake.
瞧  我再幫你的忙
Look, I'm doing you a favor.
我真的很  很感激
And I am so, so grateful.
別再抱怨了
Stop whinging.
我敢打賭  這牀可以告訴我們一些故事
I bet this bed could tell some stories.
是啊  短篇小說  恐怖故事
Yeah, short stories. Horror stories.
歡迎到倫敦  把它擡起來
Welcome to London.Well, lift it.
我覺得我在這會很開心的
I think I'm gonna be very happy here.
那是什麼氣味?
What is that smell?
洋蔥
Onions.
洋蔥和失望
Onions and disappointment.
對
Right.
沒那麼壞吧
No, it's not that bad.
沒什麼  就是掉了點油漆而已
It's nothing that a lick of paint
還有個修不了的核彈頭
and a nuclear warhead can't fix.
我有我的打字機 還有書
I've got my typewriter. I've got my books.
我在倫敦
I'm in London.
我認爲很快會沒事的
I think it's going to be all right.
我實際上可能把這些都搞定了
I might actually get things done.
你知道  你會遇到很好的人的
You know, you might actually meet someone.
Dexter 不要這樣
Dexter, please.
一個好人
A nice guy.
敏感  穿着羊毛衫
Sensitive, wears a cardigan.
我告訴過你我對這些沒興趣
I told you I'm not interested in any of that.
匹配的眼鏡 匹配的意見
Matching glasses, matching opinions.
你要去印度了  我倒是很開心
I'm actually glad you're going to India.
好  因爲我正要走 我得趕上我的航班
Good, 'cause I'm leaving. I've got to catch my flight.
這麼快?
Already?
是啊  我很抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry.
去吧  找回自己
Well, go on then. Find yourself.
繼續給我寄的這種信
Keep sending me those letters.
-長長的那種 -我會的
-Long ones. -I will.
要開心點  EM
And have fun, Em.
當然
Of course.
這是允許的
You know, it is allowed.
你知道嗎  我有一種感覺
You know, I've got a feeling that
明年這個時候
this time next year
你會像暴風般拿下倫敦
you're going to take London by storm.
請問這些菜之間的區...
What is the difference between...
玉米餅  是由小麥和玉米做的
A tortilla is either corn or wheat.
但一個玉米餅折起來塞滿東西 就是一個墨西哥煎餅
But a corn tortilla folded and filled is a taco,
而一個填滿小麥的玉米餅 就是一個玉米煎餅
whereas a filled wheat tortilla is a burrito.
炸過的玉米煎餅  就是一個油煎麪捲餅
Deep fry a burrito, it's a chimichanga.
烤過的玉米煎餅  就是一個烤玉米粉圓餅
Toast a tortilla, it's a tostada.
把它捲起來  就是玉米捲餅了
Roll it, it's an enchilada.
可以再說一次嗎?
Is there any chance you could repeat that?
你好! 我叫 Ian . Ian Whitehead
Hello. I'm Ian. Ian Whitehead.
新來的那個
The new boy.
歡迎光臨夢想的墳場
Welcome to the graveyard of ambition.
-這是廚房  -好的
-The kitchen. -All right, mate.
這些傢伙不能用微波爐
What these guys can't do with a microwave
和電炸鍋
and a deep-fat fryer.
嘿
Hey, you!
你的 美國-墨西哥 美食小組
Your basic Tex-Mex food groups.
奶酪放在鱷梨醬雞上面
Cheese on top of chicken under guacamole
豆上面是牛肉和米飯
on top of beans under rice on top of beef.
一句忠告  遠離珍寶蝦
Word of warning, avoid the jumbo prawns.
這就像俄羅斯轉盤
It's like Russian Roulette.
有六分之一機率要了你的命
One in six will kill you.
你的專業是什麼?
So what's your stroke?
我的什麼?
Sorry, my what?
服務員/演員 服務員/模型  服務員/作家?
Waiter/actor, waiter/model, waiter/writer?
好吧  我是一個喜劇演員
Well, I'm a comedian.
喜劇演員很好
We could use a comedian.
我們都喜歡笑 我知道我過去經常笑
We all like to laugh. I know I used to.
好吧   我只是剛剛真正開始
Well, I'm just starting out really.
依照我 "獨特的喜劇花式"來工作
Working on my "unique comedy stylings."
我不能開這麼多玩笑了
Not jokes so much,
要多工作  少廢話
more sort of wry, little observations.
天吶!
Ay caramba!
此刻我終於理解到一些東西
I've got this whole bit at the moment
是關於男性和女性之間的差異
about the difference between men and women.
當小夥子他們看到一個他們喜歡
How blokes, when they see a girl
的女孩  他們就會把所有...
they fancy, they get all...
-廁所 員工廁所  -噢
-Toilets. Staff toilets. -Oh.
對不起 你是在說?
Sorry. You were saying?
沒有  沒有  我今晚有一個演出
No, no. I'm doing an open mic tonight
如果你有興趣
if you were interested.
在 Laffs 之家  L - A - F - F - S
At The House of Laffs, spelled L-A-F-F-S.
這不是約會
It's not a date or anything.
你可能已經有男朋友了  你有嗎?
You've probably got a boyfriend anyway, have you?
Ian  我很想去 但下班後
Ian, I'd love to come, but after work,
我想回家吃飯  一個人待着
I like to head home, comfort eat, weep.
那麼你又怎麼樣   Emma ?
So what about you, Emma?
你最近忙什麼?
What's your stroke?
你真正做的是什麼工作?
What do you really do?
就這個  這就是我唯一的工作
Uh, this. This is what I do.
不過  不會永遠做這份  對吧
Still, it's not forever, is it?
我的房間還是那麼難聞  Tilly 把我氣死了
My room still smells. Tilly's sending me mad.
這房子簡直就是垃圾場
The flat's a dump.
我還經常發現奶酪上有老鼠的牙印
I keep finding teeth marks in the cheese
她巨大的灰色胸罩浸泡在水槽
and her big gray bras soaking in the sink.
我敢肯定這不完全是場災難
Look, I'm sure it's not a complete disaster.
倫敦在吞噬着我
London's swallowed me up.
我想我會有所作爲
I thought I'd make a difference,
但沒有人知道我在這裏
but no one knows I'm here.
聽着  好事多磨
Listen, listen. Nothing truly good was ever easy.
誰說的?
Who said that?
你
You did.
我有嗎?   煩死了
Did I? That's annoying.
真抱歉又抱怨了  我只是...
I'm sorry for moaning. I just...
我真的想聽到的...
I really wanted to hear...
教書教的怎樣?   巴黎美嗎?
How's teaching? How's Paris?
還好  EM
It's good, Em.
你知道的  真的  真的很滿足
You know, truly, really fulfilling.
不要和你的學生上牀
Well, don't sleep with any of your students.
雖然你肯定會做這種不道德的事
It's unethical and predictable.
這是很好的意見  EM  謝謝
It's good advice, Em. Thank you.
不過我得去跟媽媽吃午餐
But I've got to go and have lunch with Mum.
那  你會原諒我嗎?
Well, apologize again, will you?
我不是故意把你爸爸比喻成法西斯
I didn't mean to call your dad a fascist.
資產階級的法西斯
A bourgeois fascist.
對不起   Dexter ...
Say sorry and, Dexter...
-我的錢都快用光了  -EM?
-My money's running out. -Em? EM?
-你能聽到我嗎? -Dex ? Dex ?
-Can you hear me? -Dex ? Dex ? Dex ? Dex ?
我想你
I miss you.
晚了四十五分鐘
Forty-five minutes late.
是啊  我被攔路搶劫了
Yeah, well, I got waylaid.
你昨晚去哪了
And where were you last night?
語言學校的迪斯科舞廳
Language school disco.
-玩得開心嗎? -不  簡直就是地獄
-Was it fun? -No, it was hell.
誰一直在給你寫這些信
Tell me, who's been writing you all those long letters?
不管你的事
That is none of your business.
那個留宿的女孩?
Was it that girl who came to stay?
是啊  好吧  Emma 和我只是好朋友
Yeah. Well, Emma and I are just good friends.
你究竟需要多少假期呢?
How much holiday do you need?
我不是在度假  我在教英語
I'm not on holiday. I'm teaching English.
那不是 Alain Delon 嗎?
Isn't that Alain Delon?
什麼? 哦  不  是你的父親
What? Oh, no. It's your father.
正在挑他的雞眼 別這樣
Picking his corns. Stop it.
明天帶我去吃午餐可以嗎?
Take me for lunch tomorrow, will you?
就你和我 在一個安靜的地方
Just you and me. Somewhere quiet with white tablecloths.
我想和你談談
I want to talk to you.
爲什麼呢?  發生什麼事了?
Why? Is something wrong?
不  沒什麼
No. Nothing's wrong.
那爲什麼我們要談?
Then why do we need to talk?
真的要逼我講一個理由嗎?
Do I need a reason?
原來你在這 墮落的孩子
There you are. Degenerate.
我想你可能需要這些
Now, I thought you might want these.
謝謝  親愛的
Oh, thank you, my love.
那麼晚飯吃什麼?   千萬不要是法國菜
So what's for supper? Please, God, not French food.
你的白馬王子要見你  是嗎?
Golden Boy wants to see you. Hmm?
他又有一個新的女朋友了
He's got a new one.
-晚安 -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
-晚安  -晚安
-Night. -Good night.
-祝你幸福
- Have a good one.
我們只是接吻
We were just kissing.
你在嘗試把她整個頭塞到你的嘴裏面
You were trying to fit her entire head in your mouth.
客人沒有把菜吐出來就算好了  真噁心
People have enough trouble keeping the food down as it is.
她看中你什麼了
And what does she see in you, anyway?
她說  我是個很深奧的人
Well, she says I'm complicated.
你只是被寵壞
You're just spoiled.
老闆提出要升我做經理了
I got offered the job of manager today.
他們說只想要一個老實待着的人
They told me they wanted someone who wasn't going anywhere.
沒事  EM  聽着 我想你應該喝一瓶龍舌蘭
All right, Em, listen. I think you should take a bottle of tequila,
我想你應該走出大門
I think you should walk out the door,
我不認爲你需要回來
and I don't think you need to ever come back.
但我的工作就是我的全部
But my job is my life.
你不能因此浪費青春
You can't throw away years of your life just because,
你也覺得這很可笑
well, you think it's funny.
我的頭髮聞起來就像奶酪  Monterey Jack
My hair smells of cheese. Monterey Jack.
我以爲你一直是在寫詩
Look, I thought you were writing poetry.
什麼  去賺錢? 我試過了 失敗了
What, go where the money is? Tried that. Failed.
你就是搞不清狀況  對嗎?
You just can't see it, can you?
你很有趣  你既聰明又吸引人
Look, you're funny. You're attractive. You're smart.
我的意思是  你是我認識的最聰明的人
I mean, you're the smartest person I know.
而且你很有魅力
Sure. You are. You're attractive.
-你很性感  - 什麼?
-You're sexy. -What?
什麼?  這是性別歧視麼
What? Is that supposed to be sexist or something?
不  這不是性別歧視   只是很可笑
No, it's not sexist. It's just ridiculous.
EM  聽着
Em, listen.
如果我只可以給你一件禮物
If I could just give you one gift, all right,
爲你的後半生準備的禮物
one gift for the rest of your life,
你知不知道我會給你什麼嗎?
do you know what I'd give you?
信心
Confidence.
或者   蠟燭
It's either that or a scented candle.
來
Come here.
Emma?  我已經消毒過裝肉的冰箱
Emma? So I've disinfected the meat fridge.
你是我的英雄
My hero.
謝謝你  Ian 明天見
Thank you, Ian. See you tomorrow.
再見   夥計
Bye, mate.
再見   Emma
Bye, Emma.
我也應該去的 好吧
I should go, too. All right.
我會沒事的   我只是覺得有點迷茫
I'll be fine. I just feel a bit lost, that's all.
別這樣   每個人25歲都會迷茫
Come on, everyone's lost at 25.
你就沒有
You're not.
見習電視製片人  漂亮的新公寓  CD播放機
Trainee TV producer. Nice new flat. CD player.
星期二和星期五還可以燈紅酒綠
Group sex Tuesdays and Fridays.
沒錯  但你知道其實我也很痛苦
Yeah, but you know, I am crying on the inside.
你知道你需要什麼 不是嗎?
You know what you need, don't you?
你需要一個假期
You need a holiday.
Dexter   我只是覺得我們之間需要一些規則
Look, Dexter, all I'm saying is I think we need some rules.
規則!
Rules!
我不想讓我們的友誼冒險
I'm not taking any chances with our friendship, all right.
好  好  譬如?
All right, all right. Such as?
單獨的臥室
Separate bedrooms.
無論我們在去到哪  不可以一起睡
Wherever we stay, no shared beds,
不可以喝醉以後抱抱
no drunken cuddles.
我不明白爲什麼不能抱抱
I don't see the point of cuddling, anyway.
抱抱會讓你抽筋?
Cuddling gives you cramp.
當你同意了   然後
Agreed, then.
規則二  不準調情
Rule number two. No flirting.
不準喝了幾杯酒就活蹦亂跳的
No having a few drinks and getting frisky with me.
也不可以對其他任何人這樣
Or anyone else.
好吧  我永遠都不調情
Well, I never flirt.
我是認真的
I'm serious.
天吶  這是什麼?
Hello, what's this?
規則三
Which leads me to rule three.
-裸體條款 - 什麼?
-The nudity clause. -What?
我不想看到你淋浴的樣子  或者內個
I don't want to see you in the shower, or have a wee.
或着在淋浴的時候內個
Or have a wee in the shower.
好了  我不能保證
Well, I can't promise that.
沒商量  Dex  這是規則
You have to, Dex. It's the rules,
還有  絕對不能 裸  泳
and absolutely no skinny-dipping.
好  規則四是什麼?
All right, then. Rule number four. What?
- 不準玩拼字遊戲 -我愛拼字遊戲！
-No Scrabble. -I love Scrabble.
所以我才說是我定的規矩
That is exactly why it's my rule.
我們都還沒有死
Look, we're not dead yet.
是吧
Voil?
那是什麼?
What is that?
嗯? 我的游泳前的習慣 這叫 Edwardian
Hmm? My swimming costume. It's called the Edwardian.
不  這是你在給自己塗油漆
No, the masonry paint.
這是防曬霜 我常常被曬傷
It's factor 30. I burn.
這裏  讓我來
Here, let me.
以前我還沒有見過這東西
I've not seen this before.
什麼  ? 我在泰國的時候紋的
What, that? I got that in Thailand.
這是  陰陽
It's a yin-yang.
看上去就像一個路標
Looks like a road sign.
是啊  它的意思是"完美結合的統一體"
Yeah, well, it means "the perfect union of opposites."
它的意思是"該穿襪子啦"
It means "wear some socks."
這弄得有點低  是不是?
This is scooped a bit low, isn't it?
幸虧沒把衣服反着穿
Good job I didn't put it on backwards.
我想我要去游泳了
I think I'll go for a dip.
這是一個裸體主義者聚集的沙灘
This is a nudist beach.
不是
No, it's not.
是啊  他們在燒烤!
It is. Look. They're barbecuing!
我絕對不會全裸着燒烤
You see, I couldn't do that. Barbecue naked.
那是什麼? 瑜伽嗎?
What is that? Is that yoga?
天吶
Oh, God.
別幼稚了  繼續看你的雜誌
Grow up, all right. Back to your magazine.
我可以聽到你的思想 就像是噪音
I can hear you thinking. It's like this crunching noise.
我們不可以過去
The answer is no.
你不覺得我們脫衣服會舒服點嗎?
Don't you think we'd feel more comfortable with our clothes off?
令人難以置信 真是難以置信
Unbelievable. Just unbelievable.
爲什麼不脫呢?
Well, why not?
規則  更何況你有女朋友
The rules. Not to mention your girlfriend.
- 什麼  Ingrid? -是啊  Ingrid
-What, Ingrid? -Yeah, Ingrid.
她非常奔放
She's very uninhibited.
她在簽到的桌子上脫光了上衣
She'd have had her top off at the check-in desk.
那麼  照你一直說的
Well, as you keep pointing out,
Ingrid以前是模特
Ingrid used to be a model.
你也可以當模特
You could be a model.
目錄的模特
For a catalog or something.
我還是知道你的一些東西的
I'm just saying that we're not entirely unknown to each other
從生理角度上
from a physical point of view.
別說了  Dex
Drop it, Dex.
你知道畢業後那晚
Well, you know, that night after graduation.
別這樣  你一定記得的
Come on, you must remember.
不記得  就像被車撞了一樣完全失憶了
No. Blanked it out like a car crash.
好吧  我沒有
Well, I haven't.
事實上  如果我閉上眼睛
In fact, if I close my eyes,
我仍然可以看到你當時站在暮光中
I can still see you there just standing in the dawn light.
別這樣
Please don't.
挑釁一樣脫掉了你的工作服
Provocatively unclasping your dungarees
你向我走了過來
as you walk over to me.
我沒穿工作服
I was not wearing dungarees.
就是說你記得羅  呵呵?
So you do remember, huh?
我擋住了太陽?
Have I caught the sun?
不  你看上去...
No, you look...
很漂亮
You look fine.
你知道嗎  我沒有出過國
Do you know I've never been abroad?
什麼?   別說笑了
What? Don't be ridiculous.
這是真的
It's true.
兩週前我在Whitby和爸爸在喝湯
Fortnight in a caravan in Whitby drinking Cup-a-Soup with Dad
並試着不殺死媽媽
and trying not to kill Mum.
我無法相信我現在和你在一起
I can't believe I'm actually here with you.
爲什麼呢? 嗯?
Why? Hmm?
爲什麼?
Why?
當我們在大學  在我們第一次說話前
When we were at university, before we spoke even,
我就對你一見傾心
I had a crush on you.
-真可笑  我知道
-Ridiculous, I know.
但我們快要
But when we almost
內個的那天晚上
did it that night,
我簡直不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
我寫詩了
I wrote poems and everything.
你有什麼看法?
What have you got to say to that?
好吧  我已經知道了
Well, I already knew.
你知道自己在說什麼嗎?
What do you mean, you knew?
好吧  我猜到了幾分
Well, I sort of guessed.
所有這些史詩字母和編譯磁帶
All those epic letters and compilation tapes.
所以   發生什麼事了?
So, go on then. What happened?
嗯
Mmm.
我認識了你 你救了我
I got to know you. You cured me of you.
我還是喜歡讀那些詩
I'd still like to read those poems.
什麼詞跟 Dexter 押韻?
What rhymes with Dexter?
刺破 這是半個韻
Prick. It's a half-rhyme.
喝了太多酒了 我們應該回去了
Too much wine. We should go.
不  不  別這麼快
No, no, no. Not yet. Not yet.
我們去散步
Listen, let's go for a walk.
好吧
So this is it.
這真美
It's lovely.
喂? 這到底是怎麼回事?
Hello? What's going on here?
好吧  我想  我們應該去遊一下
Well, I thought we'd go for a quick swim.
清醒一下
Sober us up.
我明白了 我明白了
Ah, I get it. I get it.
我中了你的圈套了  對吧?
I've walked right into it, haven't I?
你讓一個女孩喝醉了   然後帶她去海邊
You get a girl drunk and lead her to a large body of water.
哦  來吧  EM  你自願的
Oh, come on, Em. Be spontaneous.
別想那麼多  放縱一下嘛
Be reckless. Live for the moment!
來吧  EM
Come on, Em. Get in!
不!
No!
你就這麼放不開 你爲什麼一直放不開呢?
You're such a prude. Why are you such a prude?
你看  來!
Look, come on!
你至少把內褲穿上吧
You could at least leave your underpants on.
規則三  還記得嗎?
Rule number three, remember?
來吧
Come on.
這是裸泳?
So this is skinny-dipping?
我要做什麼呢? 潑水?
What am I meant to do? Sort of lark about? Splash you or something?
表情很嚴肅
That's a very serious face.
你不是在內個吧
You're not having a wee, are you?
不
No.
不   我只想說
No, I just wanted to say that
我也有一樣的感覺
I felt the same.
自從我們差點內個以後
After our near-miss.
當然  我沒有寫詩  我不是瘋子
I mean, I didn't write poems or anything. I'm not insane.
但是  我想到了你
But, you know, I thought about you.
我想你
I think about you.
你和我
You and me.
真的嗎?
Really?
Really? Okay, well...
問題是我對每一個人都有這種感覺
The problem is I fancy pretty much everyone.
-我懂了  -任何人
-Oh. I see. -I mean anyone.
真的  就像我剛出獄一樣  每次都這樣
Really, I mean, it's like I've just got out of prison, all the time.
這是一個現實的問題 我可以想像
It's a real problem. I can imagine.
是啊  但跟Ingrid有關的  就是跟性有關
Yeah, and this thing with Ingrid, it's a sex thing.
這只是性愛  僅僅是性愛  完全是性愛
It's just sex, sex, sex, sex, sex.
我聽懂了  Dex
The point's been made, Dex.
但我和你  卻不一樣
But me and you, it would be different.
我想我們會希望得到不同的東西
I think we'd want different things,
我不認爲我準備好了  你懂的
and I don't think I'm ready, you know.
如果你想開心點
If you wanted to, you know, have a bit of fun,
享受假期  一身輕鬆
holiday fling, no obligations.
天吶  我當你說"不"了  行麼
Oh, God. I'll take that as a no then, shall I?
我想是這樣的 我覺得我們在一起的時刻已經過去了
I think so. I think our moment's passed.
我怎麼也說不清
Come on, I'm not expressing myself clearly.
不  不  你說清了  Dex 這就是問題所在
No, no, you are, Dex. That's the problem.
你擔心我會在意
You're worried I might care.
嘿! 嘿   回來!
Hey! Hey, Come back here!
回來 你這個...嘿!
Come back, you little... Hey!
小偷!  回來  回到這裏來
Thieves! Come back. Come back here.
等一下!
Wait!
他們已經偷了我的衣服! 你這個...
They've stolen my clothes! You little...
有人幫忙叫警察嗎? 等等!  回來!
Will someone call the police? Wait! Come back!
你別笑了  幫幫忙好嗎?
Could you please stop laughing and do something to help?
Armani  那件衣服
Armani, that suit was.
這小子 甚至把我的內褲也拿走了
The little frogs even took my underpants.
Armani? Armani?
不  Calvin Klein
No, Calvin Klein.
哦  Dex  我很抱歉
Oh, Dex, I'm so sorry.
法國鬼子!
Little French bastards!
他們還把你的帆布鞋拿走了
They took your plimsolls, too.
那不是帆布鞋  我從不穿帆布鞋
They're not plimsolls. I've never worn plimsolls in my life.
他們連一分錢都偷 我的愛死他們了!
They were penny loafers, and I bloody loved them!
什麼? 這不好笑 我犯罪的受害者
What? It's not funny. I'm a victim of crime here.
什麼?
What?
你那條C&K牌的內褲
Your Calvin Klein underpants.
我會找到他們
I'll find them.
我向你發誓 我會跟蹤他們
I swear to you, I shall track them down.
進入睡眠狀態
Go to sleep.
我不知道我們打破了多少條規則
I wonder how many rules we broke.
全部
All of them.
除了拼字遊戲
Except Scrabble.
明天就會打破了
Tomorrow, maybe.
誰說高清電視不行了?
Who says quality TV is dead?
廣告之後更精彩
Plenty more of this when we come back after the break,
所以不要走開
so do not go away.
我警告你  我們知道你住的地方
I'm warning you. We know where you live.
滾  離開這裏
Go on, get out of here.
你看  我剛打電話讓你知道這件事
Look, I just called, all right, to let you know
你是我曾經有過的最好的朋友
that you are the best friend I've ever had.
我很感動  Dex  但你自己臉都看不見了
I'm touched, Dex, but you're off your face. And?
你看  早上5 點了   回家吧
Look, it's 5:00 in the morning. Go home.
而且你一個令人難以置信的身體
And you have an incredible body.
是 Dexter ?
Is that Dexter?
答應我你會回家  好嗎?
Just promise me you'll go home, please?
我會  我會  我會 我會  我會  我會
I will, I will, I will, I will, I will, I will.
Dex  你早上還要上班  Dex ...
Dex, you have work in the morning. Dex...
晚安  好吧
Look, good night, all right?
記住  你真的很完美
Remember, you are absolutely, truly amazing.
你真了不起
You're amazing
而且出名
and famous.
我並不是那麼出名
I'm not that famous.
最近怎麼了  老頭?
Aye, aye. How are you, old man?
你母親在樓上 她早上一直在等你
Your mother's upstairs. She's been waiting all morning for you.
天哪  爲什麼你出這麼多汗呢?
Good God, why are you sweating like that?
今天很熱
Well, it's a hot day.
不
No, it's not.
她怎麼樣?
Look, how is she?
那麼  爲什麼你不自己去看看?
Well, why don't you go and see?
媽媽?
Mum?
你好  你好
Hello, hello.
你好  陌生人
Hello, stranger.
瞧  我給你買好了禮物
Look, I've got a present for you here.
這不是我送的 是 Emma 送的
It's not from me. It's from Emma.
在這裏  讓我來
Here, let me.
謝謝
Thank you.
多麼口愛
Oh, how lovely.
可能是一個小小的野心
A little ambitious maybe.
你可能會逼她寫短篇小說的
You might want to push her towards short stories in the future.
媽媽  不
Mum, don't.
你最近忙什麼?
So what have you been up to?
我是 Dexter Mayhew
I'm Dexter Mayhew.
我們已經給你準備好一個很好的表演
What a show we've got for you tonight.
我們已經有了一個...
We've got a man who claims...
跳過這一段吧
I'll skip this next bit.
接受記者採訪時 就不錯了
There's an interview that's pretty good.
也許遲點會看的
Perhaps I'll watch it later.
現場表演總是有點不平衡
The live show is always a bit patchy.
我不明白爲什麼你要用這種聲音說話
I don't understand why you have to use that voice,
但我想我不介意這樣的事情
but then I suppose I just don't care for this sort of thing.
這只是一點爲孩子們準備的小樂趣
It's just a bit of fun for kids.
他們都是喝完酒纔來看的
They just watch it after the pub.
你的意思是我不夠醉?
You mean I'm not drunk enough?
不  不是這樣的
No, it's not that.
你知道  說實話  Dexter
You know, honestly, Dexter.
在籠子裏跳舞的女孩
Dancing girls in cages.
這就是你乾的事?
Is this what it's come to?
我只是舉辦的人
I just host it.
這僅僅是達到目的的手段
It's a means to an end, that's all.
但要達到什麼目的?
But to what end?
我們總是說你可以做任何你想要做的事
We always said you could do anything you wanted.
好 你要我做什麼?
Fine. What do you want me to do?
-好事  -這就是好事
-Something good.  -It is good.
我只是做本分 瞧  這就是我能做的
I just do what I'm told. Look, this is what I can do.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
這些藥讓我糜爛
The medication makes me ratty.
我只需要躺下來  我今晚會好點的
I just need a little lie-down. I'll be better tonight.
是啊  你知道  嗯...
Yeah, you know, um...
其實  我們今晚有一場首映
Actually, I've got this premiere thingy tonight.
我很抱歉 我不能錯過侏羅紀公園
Look, I'm sorry. I can't miss it. It's Jurassic Park.
我怕我可能需要一些幫助
I'm afraid I'm going to need some help.
你沒事吧? 來  抱着我
Are you all right? Here, put your arm around me.
好了沒?
All right. All right?
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
沒事
Yes.
我可以給你什麼呢? 水? 幹馬提尼?
Can I get you anything? Water? Dry martini?
幾點了?
What time is it?
6:15 Quarter past 6:00.
是的  我必須要打瞌睡了
Yeah, I must have dozed off.
我怕你已經錯過了我們的一天
I'm afraid you've missed our day.
你父親有點生你的氣
Your father's a little angry with you.
我今晚會留下來
Look, I'll stay tonight.
不  你去吧
No. You go.
看着你跟你爸吵架很不爽
No pleasure for me watching you and your father snarling at each other.
我能說實話嗎?
Can I speak frankly?
非得說嗎?
Do you have to?
我認爲這是我的特權
I think it's my prerogative.
我知道你要當好人   體面  有愛心
I know that you're going to be a fine man. Decent, loving, accomplished.
但我不認爲你已經到達了那個水平
But I don't think you're there yet.
而現在  我很擔心
And right now, well, I worry
你已經不像以前那麼好了
that you're not very nice anymore.
對此我真沒什麼可以說
Well, there's nothing I can say to that.
你不需要說
There is nothing you have to.
我不打算跟你爭論
I'm not going to argue with you.
當你清醒的時候你可以來拿你的車
You can come and collect your car when you're sober.
你真荒謬 我的意思是你不能沒收我的車鑰匙
You're being ridiculous. I mean, you cannot confiscate my car key.
你別再侮辱我的智商!
Do not dare to insult my intelligence!
你媽媽非常愛你 你知道的
Now your mother loves you very much. You know that.
但是在她生命的最後時光...
But for whatever time she has left to her...
如果你再敢在這種狀態下來看你的母親
If you ever, ever come to see your mother in this state again,
我是不會讓你進門的
I will not let you in the house.
我會請你吃閉門羹  現在...
I will close the door in your face. Now...
走吧
Go.
好吧
Fine.
你不在   我只記得今晚你有約會
You're not there. I just remembered you're on a hot date tonight.
太遲了
I'm too late.
好吧  你收到這個的時候你可以給我打電話嗎?
Okay, can you call me when you get this?
我只是想跟別人說說話
It's just I need to speak to someone.
不是別人  是你
Not someone. You.
一隻電鋸裝在手臂上  這真是瘋了
A chainsaw for an arm. It was mad.
這真是驚天地泣鬼神的作品
It's a work of timeless beauty.
我覺得這是最好的三部曲
It's the finest of the trilogy, methinks.
而我不看 鬼玩人 頭兩部都能看懂它
And I still understood it without seeing Evil Dead I or Evil Dead II.
我唯一的抱怨是這不夠暴力
My only complaint would be that there wasn't enough violence.
你不介意吧
You didn't mind, did you?
你想看 藍色情挑 ?
Or did you want to see Three Colors: Blue?
我要跳過開胃菜因爲我有這些玉米片
I'm gonna skip a starter because I had those nachos,
但你可以繼續  你可以點任何你喜歡的東西
but you go ahead. You can have anything you like.
什麼菜值14英鎊以上?
Anything up to the value of, say, 14.00?
不  不  說真的  沒有
No, no, seriously, no, have anything.
你知道 理性地說
Well, you know, within reason.
能再次見到你真好
It's just so good to see you again.
你將會成爲一個了不起的老師
And you're going to be an amazing teacher.
-恭喜  -謝謝
-Congratulations. -Thanks.
我希望我有更多像你一樣的老師
I wish I'd had more teachers like you.
只是我還沒有做過任何工作  Morley 老師
Not that I'd have got any work done. Miss Morley.
-你有沒有新的消息-
-You have no new messages.-
喜劇是一個殘酷的情婦
Comedy's a cruel mistress.
有時  Emma  我認爲唯一的辦法
Sometimes, Emma, I think the only way
能讓我看到我的名字被投射燈照着
I'm going to see my name up in lights
就是我把名字改成 "緊急出口"
is if I change it to Emergency Exit.
無論如何  我今晚要即興創作
Anyway, I'm doing an improvisation night at the moment.
咔咔嘻 不是他的真名
Mr. Giggles. Not his real name.
但我覺得我要去堅持找更多的觀測資料
But I think I'm gonna stick to the more observational material.
現在我完全明白了
I've got this whole thing at the moment
貓狗之間的差異
about the difference between cats and dogs.
嘿   別說了
Hey, please stop.
好了 你知不知道當一個喜劇演員
Okay. Do you know what the hardest thing
最難的是什麼嗎?
about being a stand-up comedian is?
是它的衣服嗎?
Is it the clothes?
好極了  不
Very good. No.
是人們期望你在所有的時間都能搞笑
It's that people expect you to be on all the time.
因爲如果你不搞笑   那麼你是什麼?
Because if you're not being funny, then what are you being?
Ian  這不是表演
Ian, it's not a performance.
人生就是一場表演 不是嗎?
Except it sort of is, though, isn't it?
我看到你就已經這麼激動  激動過頭了
I've been so excited about seeing you. Like nervous.
對不起  我...
I'm sorry, I...
我也不擅長這東西
I'm no good at this stuff, either.
只是現在我已經畢業了
It's just I graduated today.
我終於有資格做一些有用的東西
I'm finally, actually qualified to do something useful,
而我想與人慶祝
and I wanted to celebrate with someone.
Dexter 很忙嗎?
Was Dexter busy?
EM  當你聽到這些
Em, when you hear this,
你能不能打車過來?
can you just get in a cab?
我會幫你給錢的
And I'll pay.
也許你甚至可以在沙發上過夜
Maybe you could even stay over, you know, on the sofa or something?
我只是想見到你
I need to just see you.
你能過來一下嗎?
Please, can you just come over?
Emma Morley? 嗯?
Emma Morley? Hmm?
我能說些什麼嗎?
Can I say something?
說吧
Go on.
我想你完全就是胡說八道
I think you are the absolute bollocks.
你跟你的甜言蜜語
You, with your honeyed words.
我也許該回家了
I should probably head home.
不要走  讓我們去別的地方
Don't go. Let's go somewhere else.
我住的附近
I live near,
其實我的意思是
actually. I mean,
它就像垃圾場  太可怕了
it's a dump, like, horrible.
但我有音樂和酒
But I've got music and booze.
或者熱的乳白的飲料   只要你喜歡
Or a hot, milky drink if you prefer.
我們可以再來一杯阿華田
We could go on an Ovaltine bender.
好吧  一  二  三  走!
All right. Okay. One, two, three, go!
怎麼走?
Which way?
這邊  這邊  這邊!
This way, this way, this way!
我根本不需要   這只是友情
That's not needy. That's just affection.
我只是想給予更多的愛
I've just got a lot of love to give.
那麼  如果我不能給你打電話  我能來看看你嗎?
Well, if I can't call you, can I come and see you?
你知道火柴都在哪裏嗎?
Do you know where the matches are?
不
No.
你可能要離開幾分鐘  走吧
You might wanna leave it for a couple of minutes. Go.
嗨  Morley老師  嗨
Hi, Miss Morley. Hi.
之後那裏將會有一個娛樂圈的聚會
There gonna be a showbiz party afterwards
有香檳 小吃和清脆的笑聲嗎?
with champagne, and canap and the tinkle of laughter?
這是一個學校的戲劇表演  Ian
It's a school play, Ian.
我懷疑我們可以九時半前回到家
I suspect we'll be home by half 9:00.
你爲什麼不換換口味住在我家?
Why don't you stay at mine for a change?
我會洗我的被套的
I'll wash my duvet cover.
這是你的男朋友嗎  Morley小姐
Is that your boyfriend, Miss Morley?
真無恥
Oy! Cheeky.
問候  男孩和女孩  歡迎
Greetings, boys and girls. Welcome to the Late Night Lock In.
一號攝影機  Dexter
Camera one, Dexter.
表演已經吃了  生活和響亮
The show that is late, live and loud.
Dexter  有位先生想見你
Dexter, gentleman to see you.
注意電線  先生
Mind the cables, sir.
好了  各位
Hey. Okay, ladies.
我自己去喝茶吃包子
I helped myself to tea and buns.
我希望我不會讓你陷入困境
I hope I'm not going to get you into trouble.
我相信它會沒事
I'm sure it'll be fine.
他在那兒! 嘿!
There he is! Hey!
他不覺得自己看起來很華麗嗎? 來 Suki
Doesn't he look gorgeous? Come to Suki.
Suki Sue 來這裏
Suki Sue. Come here.
我只想把你吃到骨頭都不剩
I just want to eat you up.
Suki  看  這是我的父親
Suki, actually, look, this is my father.
Wotcha  M 先生
Wotcha, Mr. M.
你的兒子是不是太奢華了?
Isn't your son gorgeous?
嗯  他是非常好人的
Um, he's very nice.
M 夫人在哪裏?
And where's Mrs. M?
可悲的是她離開了人世
Sadly, she passed away.
Barry  我需要一些水
Barry, I need some water.
真是一個可怕的女人
What an appalling woman.
其實她算是我的女朋友吧
Actually, she's sort of my girlfriend.
哦  祝賀你
Oh, well, congratulations.
你會讓你的母親很失望的
Your mother would have been most impressed.
謝謝  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
我會在家裏看  如果我能保持清醒
I'll be watching at home if I can stay awake.
玩得開心
Have fun
不要理會他們在報紙上說什麼
and don't take any notice of what they say in the papers.
好的  先生  請到這邊來
Okay, sir. If you'd like to come this way.
請
Please.
我的車毀人亡電視臺的臺長
I'm the king of car crash television.
但是你是國王  這很好
But you're the king of it. That's good.
標題下的照片  " 可惡"
Caption under photo. "Odious."
你爲什麼不能再來一次?
Why can't you come again?
因爲我在工作
Because I'm working.
我會派車來接你
I'll send a car to come and pick you up.
Dex  我不能
Dex, I can't.
我知道  我很抱歉
I know, and I'm sorry.
你在我身邊的時候我感覺好多了
I'm just so much better when you're around.
你看   我只是擔心我會變得
Look, I'm just worried I'm gonna be
站在相機前面思考
stood in front of the camera thinking,
" 什麼是血腥點? "
"What's the bloody point?"
這表演太荒謬了  我真是一個騙子  EM
The show's ridiculous. I'm such a fraud, Em.
別這樣  這就夠了
Hey, come on. That's enough.
你知道你在做什麼  你會沒事的
You know what you're doing. You'll be fine.
對
Right.
不要用這種奇怪的聲音說話好嗎?
Just don't speak in that weird voice, okay?
好  好吧  再見
Okay. All right. Bye.
準備好  在這裏  我們來了
Get ready. Here we go.
偉大的東西 讓我們行動起來 讓我們行動起來!
Great stuff. Let's move. Let's move!
好吧  來吧   夥計們  走吧
Okay, come on, guys. Let's go.
我們上臺了  超級巨星
We're on, superstar.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
歡迎來到 Late Night Lock In
welcome to Late Night Lock In.
這演出很新  生動...
The show that is late, live...
而響亮!
And loud!
今晚我們爲你準備的節目是不是很精彩呢
And what a show we've got for you tonight.
幹得好  親愛的
Well done, darling.
謝謝
Thank you.
來吧  Morley 小姐
Come on, Miss Morley.
好樣的!
Bravo!
Maxi Crew  女士們  先生們
The Maxi Crew, ladies and gentlemen.
The Maxi Crew The Maxi Crew.
坐下吧   夥計們  坐  你可以坐那
All right, take a seat, fellas. Take a seat. You can sit down there.
好  夥計們  開始我只是想說那果醬很新鮮
Right, guys, I just wanna start by saying that that jam was fresh.
好吧   別管那些... 讓我們問一些問題
Right, okay, so let's kick it off with... Let's ask some questions.
什麼是HIP-HOP? 這是街上的聲音?
What is hip hop? Is this the voice from the street?
這就是你們這麼生氣的原因嗎?
Is this why you guys are just so angry?
不  dawg
No, dawg.
It's chill, it's chill, it's chill. It's chill, it's chill, it's chill.
對   沒關係
Right, okay.
聽着  您可以用任何事情RAP嗎?
Listen, can you rap about anything?
例如  你能就一個奶酪三明治RAP嗎?
For example, could you rap about a cheese sandwich?
你是新來的? 你有沒有這樣做過?
Are you new here? Have you done this before?
哦  親愛的 不要在家裏嘗試這個
Oh, dear. Do not try this at home.
Ian? Ian?
你認爲你今天可以把油漆塗完嗎?
Do you think you'll finish painting today?
我想至少可以把電視放回來
I'd like to at least get the TV back inside.
好  我可以先吃早餐嗎?
All right, all right. I can have breakfast first, can't I?
我們已經吃過早餐了
We've had breakfast.
那就吃早午餐
All right, brunch, then.
早午餐  它是午餐嗎?  它是早餐嗎?
Brunch. Is it lunch? Is it breakfast?
不  它是早午餐  難道是早晚餐?
No, it's brunch. What about brinner, say?
還是早中餐?
Or brupper?
好吧  我應該繼續
Well, I should get on.
我想我們同意 snooth 這件事
I thought we agreed about snootch?
看來這幾天我說什麼都錯  對吧?
I can't seem to say anything right these days, can I?
如果你今晚不想我去...
Look, if you don't want me to go tonight...
不  你應該去
No, you should go.
或如果你想跟我們一起去...
Or if you wanted to come with us...
什麼?  跟Dexter 見面   然後你們都討論我
What? Dexter ignoring me, and you talking over me?
別管我  謝謝
No, thank you.
不會那樣的
It won't be like that.
況且  今晚我有一個演出
Anyway, I've got a gig tonight
在 The Rose & Crown, Sir Laffalots
at The Rose & Crown, Sir Laffalots.
有償演出?
Paid gig?
不
No.
我還是回去寫東西了
Better get back to it then.
三十四篇寫 Lord of the Flies 的散文
Thirty-four identical essays on Lord of the Flies.
EM? 大概1700小時
Em? About 1700 hours,
你會不會想要一點...
do you fancy a little bit of the old...
你懂的?
You know,  Afternoon delight?
哇!
Wow!
你看上去令人難以置信
You look incredible.
哦...噢!
Oh... Ooh!
讓我們來看看禮服
Let's see the dress.
它是復古的嗎?
Is it vintage?
不  這是全新的
No, it's brand new.
真的嗎? 嗯
Really? Mmm.
嗯  你看起來棒極了  我愛你的鞋子
Well, you look great, and I love the shoes.
謝謝  它是世界第一的高跟鞋
Thank you. It's the world's first orthopedic high heel.
太長時間沒見了  EM
Look, it's been too long, Em.
今晚我找些樂子
I need to have some fun tonight.
我們可以玩的開心點嗎  求你了?
Can we have fun, please?
天吶  對不起
God, sorry.
給我兩秒鐘  這是工作
Look, I'll be two seconds. It's work.
我沒穿衣服!
I'm naked!
Suki  你這個瘋子
Suki, you nutter.
你在哪裏?
Where are you, baby?
我想你應該在聚會
I thought you were supposed to be at the party.
你知道他們會損害你的大腦?
You do know they damage your brain?
他們不會破壞你的大腦
They do not damage your brain.
你怎麼知道?
How can you tell?
哈哈  很可笑  EM
Ha ha, very funny, Em.
我向你保證   只需要一年  你就會有一臺
I guarantee you, one year, one year, and you'll have one of these.
那好 如果我得到一臺手機  你就請我吃晚餐
You're on. If I ever get a mobile phone, you can buy me dinner.
什麼?
What, again?
來吧  喜劇之王怎麼樣?
So, come on. How's the king of comedy?
哦  Ian 沒事 我們都很好
Oh, Ian's fine. We both are.
你是否還那麼愛對方呢?
Are you still very much in love?
他打嗝都可以打出一隊人  我是血肉之軀
He can belch the theme to The A-Team. I'm only flesh and blood.
我不知道 這些天來 我們似乎沒有...
I don't know. These days, we don't seem to...
新的地方如何?  怎麼樣?
And how's the new place? How's that?
房子還不錯  一個房間
Flat's fine. Well, it's a room and a half in murder mile.
Ian 6個月以來一直想要
And Ian's been talking about painting
給那堵牆刷油漆
the same wall for the past six months.
但它有潛力 有很好的風景 還有煤氣廠
But it's got potential. There's a view. The Gasworks.
你應該來看看的
You should come round.
MMM! 嗯
Mmm! Mmm.
Suki 怎樣了?
How's Suki?
哦  她太棒了  簡直就是華麗
Oh, she's fantastic. Yeah, gorgeous.
我非常欣賞她的是她真正理解這一行
What's great for me is that she really understands the industry.
她確切地知道那種感覺是...
You know, she knows exactly what it's like to be...
我會說" 出名"  我們恨這個單詞
I was gonna say "famous." God, we hate the word.
每次我看電視轉檯
Every time I turn on the telly,
她就穿着粉色橡膠緊身衣出現在我面前
she's there in a pink rubber catsuit.
她的表現出乎意料的好
She's doing incredibly well.
啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah.
好吧  我們都是
Well, we both are.
我想到了一些真的真的很令人興奮的東西
I've got some really, really exciting stuff coming up.
都在醞釀當中
It's all sort of in development.
如果我告訴你  我不得不開槍打死你
If I told you, I'd have to shoot you.
請開槍吧
Please do.
沒關係   別管我  好嗎?
Never mind. Start without me, all right?
你好!
Hello.
真有你的  好好享受吧
There you are. Enjoy.
你在做無聊的事情嗎?
What are you doing, you silly thing?
好吧  聽着  我們遲點再討論
Well, listen, we'll talk later.
看看這華麗的外表
Look at this. This looks gorgeous.
你沒事吧? 也許她可以加入我們?
Are you all right? Maybe she could join us?
嘿  嘿  你在說什麼?
Hey, hey, hey, what's this?
我來這裏看你  還記得嗎?
I'm here to see you, remember?
對  教書教的怎麼樣了?
Right, well, how's the teaching?
什麼? 如果你不感興趣   就別問
What? If you're not interested, don't ask.
我很感興趣
I am interested.
我只是想你正要寫這本小說
I just thought you were going to be writing this novel, that's all.
我會的  但我要賺錢
And I will. But I have to earn a living.
更重要的一點  我喜歡它
More to the point, I enjoy it.
我是一個好老師  Dexter
I'm a bloody good teacher, Dexter.
你絕對是
I'm sure you are.
不過  你知道他們說什麼?
Still, you know what they say?
不  他們怎麼說?
No, what do they say?
你知道  "那些..."
You know, "Those who can..."
不  我很抱歉  我不熟悉這些  繼續吧
No, I'm sorry. I'm not familiar. Finish the sentence.
好  "有能力的人就幹一番大事
All right. Well, "Those who can, do,
"沒有能力的,就跑去教書"
"and those who can't, teach."
而教書的人就說 "去他媽的! "
And those who can teach say, "Go fuck yourself!"
EM! EM   無論我做了什麼  我很抱歉
Em! Em, come on. Look, whatever I've done, I'm sorry.
你明顯喝多了
You've obviously had a bit too much to drink.
不  你醉了!  你醉了!
No, you're drunk! You're drunk!
你知道三年來我沒見過你真正清醒的樣子
Do you realize that I have literally not seen you sober for three years?
每10 分鐘跑去上一趟廁所
Nipping off to the toilet every 10 minutes.
要麼你是在吸毒  或者你有痢疾
Either you're on coke, or you've got dysentery.
無論哪種方式  都很無聊
Either way, it's boring!
你在浪費自己的青春
Banging on about yourself all the time.
好吧  我不會介意   Dex
Well, I wouldn't mind, Dex,
但你是一個電視節目主持人  對吧
but you're a TV presenter, all right?
你並沒有發明青黴素
You've not invented penicillin.
你要做的就是站在一旁
All you do is stand around shouting,
喊 " 製造一些噪音吧"!
"Make some noise!"
你看  我很快樂
Look, I am having fun, that's all.
我最近經歷了很多
I've been through a lot recently.
我可能會有點不在狀態
I might get a bit carried away,
但如果你不停止責備我...
but if you wouldn't stop getting at me...
我不是故意的  而且...
Am I? I don't mean to, and I...
我知道你和你的媽媽一起經歷了很多
I know that you've been through a lot with your mum and all, I know.
但有一些事情我需要你談談
But, there are things that I needed to talk to you about.
關於我是如何被困在這間房子的
About how I am stuck in this flat
跟一個我不愛的人住在在一起
with a man that I am not in love with.
如果我不能跟你這些
And if I can't talk to you,
那你在這裏又有什麼意義呢?
then what is the point of you? Of us?
你是什麼意思 "這有什麼意義呢?"
What do you mean, "What's the point?"
我認爲我們已經沒有共同語言了
I think we've outgrown each other.
不  你已經看不起我了
No, you have outgrown me.
你覺得我不夠酷  很沉悶
You think I'm uncool and dreary.
我不認爲你沉悶  EM...
I don't think you're dreary. Em...
我認爲如果這一切都結束了
I think if it's over,
那麼我們就應該面對事實  說再見了
then we should just face facts. Say goodbye.
這聽起來像你要甩我
It sounds like you're dumping me.
是啊  也許我是
Yeah, maybe I am.
你已經不是曾經的你了
You're not who you used to be.
來吧  EM  我道歉!
Come on, Em. Look, I apologize!
請
Please.
來吧 就是這樣
Come on. That's it.
來
There.
我愛你   Dexter  很深很深
I love you, Dexter. So much.
我只是不再喜歡你了
I just don't like you anymore.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Johnny Cage  獲勝
Johnny Cage wins.
這是一個全能取勝王
That's an almighty win from the Blade Cruisers there.
我想你們都會同意   幹得好   夥計們
I think you'll all agree. Well done, guys.
今晚就到此結束   下週再見
That's all from tonight's Joy Stick Jockeys. Join us next week
當我們回顧你的控制檯遊戲
when we review the smoking hot new console games coming at you.
直到那時  夜貓們  繼續遊戲吧
Until then, night owls, keep gaming.
我真的要說"火得冒煙"?
Do I really have to say "smoking hot"?
看在上帝的份上  我都32歲了
It's just I'm 32, for God's sake.
什麼  他們解僱我?
What, they're sacking me?
你看   解僱這個詞有負面的含義
You see, sack has negative connotations.
他們只是想嘗試錄用一個新的主持人
It's just they wanna try a new presenter.
因此他們解僱我嗎?
So they are sacking me?
哦  不  他們正在考慮一個不同的節目
Well, no, they're taking the show in a different direction,
跟你的節目大相徑庭
but it's a direction away from you.
好了  你已經沒有以前那麼上鏡了
Okay, so less you now.
好了
Okay.
你20歲的時候更自我
More you in your 20s.
對
Right. Right.
那麼  好消息是?
So, what's the good news?
對不起?
Sorry?
好了  你說你有一些壞消息  好消息呢?
Well, you said you had some bad news. What's the good news?
每個人的事業都會跌宕起伏
Every career has its ups and downs.
這僅僅是一次小小的挫折
This is just a bloody great down.
我感覺自己終於醒悟了  Dexy
And I sense a bit of disenchantment, Dexy.
只是有點擔心我的未來
Just a little concerned about my future.
它並不完全是我期待的東西
It's not quite what I was expecting.
未來是不可預測的  這就是它令人興奮的原因
The future never is. That's what makes it so bloody exciting!
人人都愛你  是嗎?
Everyone loves you, yeah?
但他們用一種由愛生恨的
But they love you in that ironic,
無比諷刺的方式來愛你
love-to-hate kind of way.
對不對?  我們需要做的
Right? And all that we need to do
就是找一個真正愛你的人
is just find someone that loves you for real.
可以嗎? 是啊
Okay? Yeah.
我愛你  Sylvie
I love you, Sylvie.
不  不  等一下  不  我愛上你了
No, no, wait. No, I'm in love with you.
你看  我從來沒有和別人說過
Look, I've never said this to anyone before.
嗯  這是一個謊言 嗯...
Well, that's a lie. Um...
我愛你  Sylvie 我...
I love you, Sylvie. I...
Sylvie 告訴我你以前頗有名氣
Sylvie tells me you used to be quite well known.
電視節目主持人還是
TV presenter or something.
我以前是主持人
I did. Yeah. Once upon a time.
是的  在 Larginit臺的那個節目
Yes, on Larginit. That program.
你還記得嗎?
Do you remember,
媽咪?
Mummy?
你以前很討厭它的
You used to really hate it.
是啊
Yes.
"把它關掉"她老說
"Turn it off," she used to say.
"關掉它  它會殺死你的腦細胞"
"Turn it off. It's killing your brain cells."
那是你  是嗎?
That was you, was it?
你仍然在電視臺工作嗎  Dexter ?
You still work in television, Dexter?
沒有以前那麼多了
Not so much, no.
有點漸行漸遠的感覺  真的
That sort of drifted away, really.
嗯
Uh-huh.
Dexter  只是謙虛  他得到很多的錄用
Dexter's just being modest. He gets lots of offers.
無論如何  他真正的想要做的是製作
Anyway, what he really wants to do is produce.
聚會的遊戲
Party games.
你在嗎? Moriarty
Are you there, Moriarty?
在這裏
Here.
兩個不錯的工作   太好了
Two for two, nice work, bro.
來一個帽子戲法
Going for a hat trick.
你在嗎? Moriarty
Are you there, Moriarty?
在這裏
Here.
人羣要沸騰了!
The crowd goes wild!
我的孩子!
There's my boy!
下一次運氣會更好的  孩子  謝謝
Better luck next time, son. Thank you.
好吧  我仍然爲你感到非常自豪
Well, I'm still very proud of you.
哦   這個是不是很有趣的?
Oh, isn't this fun?
-Dexter  介不介意帶上我? -哦  不
-Dexter, care to take me on? -Oh, no.
這是一個了不起的的想法
That's a terrific idea.
親愛的  您確定嗎?
Darling, are you sure?
是的  我肯定
Yes, I'm sure.
來吧  第一章 拿起你的武器
Come on, chap. Pick up your weapon.
很好  媽媽
Nice and tight, Mum.
-好嗎? -好
-All right? - All right.
-非常好  -我們不希望你作弊
-Very good. - We don't want you cheating.
祝你好運  好
Good luck. All right.
來吧  姐姐
Come on, sis.
好   準備好了嗎?
All right, ready?
準備好了...
As ready as I'll...
天吶! 你認爲你正在做什麼是?
Good God, man! What the hell do you think you're doing?
這桌子是來自意大利  我很抱歉
That table was from Italy. I'm so sorry.
我必須從一個有趣的角度打到她
I must have just caught her at a funny angle there.
你甚至不問她在不在那裏  Moriarty
You didn't even ask if she was there, Moriarty.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你看  我不知道我在想什麼
Look, I don't know what I was thinking.
看在我的份上不要換鎖了
Serves me right for not changing the locks.
向好的方面看  Ian
Looking good, Ian.
你可以吃飽  Emma
You can get stuffed, Emma.
這就是你的行爲?
Is that from your act?
沒有  雖然我最近有新東西做
No, though I have got this new thing I've been working on.
天吶
God.
我來了
I come on,
說  " 這裏有一個有趣的故事
and I say, "Here's a funny story.
您一定會喜歡這個"
You'll like this."
Ian  "有一個人
Ian. "There's this guy,
"和他的女朋友出去玩  他很愛慕她
"and he's going out with this girl, and he worships her,
"他們一起買了一套房子
"and they buy this flat together.
" 然後他還送了她訂婚戒指和很多別的東西
"And then he gets her an engagement ring, the lot.
"結果卻是她還愛着她最好的朋友"
"It turns out that she is still in love with her best friend."
這真有趣  Ian
Interesting theory, Ian,
只是我已經很長時間沒見 Dexter  了
except I've not seen Dexter for ages.
-沒有?  -這不是原因
-No?  -That is not the reason.
你知道他是如何發現的嗎? 他從她的詩中發現的
Do you know how he found out about it? He read it in her poetry.
你這個混蛋!
You bastard!
-還給我! -"我們的畢業之夜!
-Give it back to me! -"Our graduation night!
" 同牀共枕"
"The erotic intensity of the shared bed."
"在法國神奇的一週" 這一切都在這詩裏面
"That magic week in France." It's all here in blank verse.
如果你再敢來這裏 我就打電話報警!
If you ever, ever, come in here again I will call the police!
打電話給天煞的警察! 這是我的房子!
Call the bloody police! It's my flat, too!
是嗎? 我付了抵押貸款!
Is it? I paid the mortgage!
你只是坐在周圍放屁
You just sat around farting and
看着星際迷航-可汗之怒!
watching the bloody Wrath of Khan!
你愛可汗之怒
You love The Wrath of Khan.
我恨可汗之怒
I hate The Wrath of Khan.
幸虧我們沒有結婚
It's a good job we didn't get married.
對不起我用過你所有的東西
I'm sorry about going through all your stuff.
我最近有點生氣  僅此而已
I've just been a bit mad recently, that's all.
沒事
It's all right.
我想念你
I miss you.
我知道
I know you do.
就像就在這裏
Like, right here.
要麼... 我不知道
Either that, or it's trapped wind. I'm not sure.
無論怎樣  一切都會過去的
Either way, it'll pass.
你的書寫的很好
It's good, by the way.
不是詩  那些詩很糟糕
Not the poems. The poems are awful,
但其他的東西  那故事  你真好笑
but the rest of the stuff, the stories. You're funny.
適當的滑稽
Proper funny.
-不像我  -Ian
-Not like me. -Ian.
不   我只是說你應該把他們展示給別人
No, I'm just saying that you should show them to someone,
因爲你低估了自己
because you're better than you know.
哦!
Oh!
那是 Emma Morley 我大學同學
So that's Emma Morley. We went to university together.
你也跟她睡過嗎?
Did you sleep with her as well?
沒有
No.
那新娘呢?
What about the bride?
不  天吶  你在說什麼?
No. God, what is this?
每個週末我們都會去一個婚禮
It's just that every weekend we go to a wedding
跟你睡過的能裝下一車了
with a coachload of people that you've slept with.
這就像一個會議
It's like a conference.
好了 來吧
Okay. Come on.
你知道你是我的唯一
You know you're the only one for me now.
你是  來吧  來這裏  來這裏
You are. Come on, come here. Come here.
鷹嘴豆泥  有機果汁
Hummus wraps. Organic smoothies.
公平貿易的咖啡
Fair Trade coffees.
小龍蝦  Dex  人們都爲這小傢伙發瘋
Crayfish. Dex, people go crazy for the little buggers.
我已經得到了12家分行了 年底會有另外12 家
I've got 12 branches already. Twelve more by the end of the year.
最近我聽到一些謠言
Well, you know, there's a rumor going around
說其實你是超有錢的人
that you're actually a multi millionaire.
不是吧
Come on.
怎樣才叫超有錢
Well, define multi.
你應該來吃午飯  我們應該談
You should come and have lunch. We should talk.
什麼  你想給我一份工作嗎?
What, are you offering me a job?
不   我只是說...
No, I'm just saying...
你給我一份工作  對吧?
You are, aren't you? You're offering me a job.
你看  我沒見過你 電視上一段時間
Look, I haven't seen you on telly for a while.
我想如果你想要一個新的開始...
I thought if you wanted a fresh start...
Callum   夥計
Callum, mate. Mate, mate, mate.
在大學  你穿同樣的牛仔褲...
At university, you wore the same pair of jeans for...
穿了大概  4年?
What was it, four years?
很久以前的事了
Long time ago now, pal.
我們已經不是學生了
We're not students anymore.
似乎有人要享受它
Someone seems to be enjoying it.
瞧  看看這裏
Look, look over here.
你有沒有 見過 Emma Morley?
Have you seen Emma Morley?
一直就在我們眼前 啊?
Right under our noses all this time. Eh?
誰知道?
Who knew?
我靜靜坐着  默默等待
I sit and wait
是不是天上的天使
Does an angel
在考慮着我的命運
Contemplate my fate
他們是否知道
Do they know
我告訴你  一個發現改變了我的生活
I tell you, the one discovery changed my life.
小龍蝦
Crayfish.
我已經得到了12家分行
I've got 12 branches already.
今年年底會有另外12 家
Another 12 by the end of the year.
我告訴 Dexter 他會有很多機會
I was telling Dexter there's plenty of opportunities.
親愛的  我很快會回來的
Darling, I'll be back in a bit.
你想一些香檳嗎?
Do you want some champagne?
這不是香檳  是西班牙語
It's not champagne. It's Spanish.
當我趴在我的牀上的時候
When I'm lying in my bed
思緒緩緩飄過我的腦海
Thoughts running through my head
我再也不相信愛情了
And I feel that love is dead
我愛的是天使
I'm loving angels instead
你想離開這裏嗎?
Do you want to get out of here?
是的   請
Yes, please.
她通過這一切提供我保護
And through it all She offers me protection
很多憐愛
A lot of love and affection
跟新娘睡過  讓你覺得今天很難過吧
Today must be quite tough for you, having slept with the bride.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
什麼? 你怎麼知道所有這些事情的
What? How do you know all these things?
Tilly 告訴我所有關於它的事了嗎?
Tilly told me all about it. Oh, did she?
足部按摩到一半兩人都失控了
The foot massage spun out of control.
我想你甚至用了我的橄欖油
I think you even used my olive oil.
腳印踩到了廚房牆壁上
Footprints halfway up the kitchen wall.
嗯  我已經沒再想這些了  所以...
Well, that stuff's behind me now, so...
說真的   什麼事?
Really, what happened?
在洗手間內個已經沒有感覺了麼?
Sex in toilet cubicles lose its bittersweet charm?
狂歡不會讓你在夜裏感到一絲溫暖  Emma
Well, an orgy won't keep you warm at night, Emma.
當你老的時候狂歡不可能照顧你
An orgy won't look after you when you're old.
說得好
Well said.
無論如何  我搞砸了我的職業生涯
Anyway, I screwed up my career.
搞砸了媽媽的事情
And screwed up things with Mum.
事實並非如此
That's not true.
而我搞砸了我跟她的友誼
And I screwed up my friendships.
然後Sylvie剛剛來到我身邊
And then Sylvie just came along.
她算是救了我  真的
And she sort of, well, saved me, really.
她很漂亮
She's very beautiful.
當然  她絕對沒有幽默感
Of course, she has absolutely no sense of humor.
差不多吧  他的幽默一直被高估了
Just as well. A sense of humor's overrated.
像傻瓜一樣總是在身邊
Goofing around all the time.
唯一一次伊Ian 真的讓我笑起來
The only time Ian ever really made me laugh
就是當他從樓梯上掉下來的時候
was when he fell down the stairs.
Sylvie  你知道  她不喜歡笑
Well, you know, Sylvie says she doesn't like to laugh.
真的不太喜歡她不笑的樣子
Doesn't really like what it does to her face.
但你愛她  對?
But you love her, right?
是啊  我崇拜她
Yeah, I worship her.
我愛 Colin
I'm loving Colin instead
哦  不  不  這邊走
Oh, no, no. This way.
我們去哪兒?
Where are we going?
哦!
Oh!
來吧  是吧?
So, come on, then. You, huh?
浪漫嘛?
Any romance?
不要說這種東西  Dex
Don't start, Dex.
什麼?
What?
同情的話  我孤獨但不孤單
Your sympathy. I'm not lonely. I'm alone.
那裏  聽起來怎麼樣?
There, how'd that sound?
啊  是啊  我買了
Yeah, yeah. I bought that.
這是真的
It's true.
這本書讓我感覺自己稍微有點進步了
I've got a tiny advance to write this book.
其實我也有事要告訴你
Well, you know, I have something to tell you, too.
你要結婚了
You're getting married.
是啊
Yeah.
你高興嗎?
So, you're pleased?
我當然很高興  Dex   太好了
Of course I'm pleased, Dex. Fantastic news, really.
是香味嗎?  你的婚禮邀請函很香
Scented? Your wedding invitations are scented.
是啊  薰衣草
Yeah, lavender.
Dex  它的錢  他們聞到錢的味道了
No, Dex, it's money. They smell of money.
8月14日?
August 14th?
是的  我認爲這就是  強婚
Yeah, I think that's what they call a shotgun wedding.
爲了350
For 350.
自助的
With buffet.
你知不知道父親是誰?
Do you know who the father is?
停止它
Stop it.
我開玩笑
I'm kidding.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
謝謝
Thank you.
爸爸  我知道
A dad. I know.
可以這樣? 他們會讓你這樣做?
Is that allowed? Will they let you?
真是不可思議  對嗎?
It's incredible, isn't it?
你會成爲一個很好的父親
You're going to be a wonderful father.
你真的這麼認爲嗎?
Do you really think so?
確定一定以及肯定
I don't doubt it for a minute.
我想念你  Dex
I missed you, Dex.
好吧  我也很想你
Well, I missed you, too.
不要再突然消失
No more disappearing.
好  我不會再消失  如果你不會
No, well, I won't if you won't.
-嗯? -恩
-Mmm?  -Mmm. MMM?
我們該回去了
We should go.
當然可以  我們走吧
Absolutely, let's go.
別這樣  Jasmine  別這樣
Come on, Jasmine. Come on.
別這樣   別哭了好嗎?
Come on. You gonna stop crying?
你最近怎樣?
How you getting on?
好  是啊  是啊
Good, mate. Good. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
不太符合我所期待  但...
Not quite what I was expecting, but...
你是什麼意思?
How do you mean?
好了  你看到有機及自制這幾個字了...
Well, you see the words organic and homemade...
我知道 你在想象有幾個嬉皮士
Yeah, I know. You imagined a couple of hippies
在某個小農場  生產自己的麥片
on a little farm somewhere, knitting their own muesli.
好主意  但這是商業  Dex
Nice idea, but this is business, Dex.
-我明白了 -這是你的最後兩個
-Yeah, well, I realize that. -Here's your last two.
聽着  你只在這裏學習竅門的  好嗎?
Listen, mate. You're only here to learn the ropes, okay?
公司的政策   每個人都必須遵循
Company policy. Everyone has to.
Callum   我喜歡它
Callum, I'm enjoying it.
老實說  我很好
Honestly, I'm good.
還有很多奶粉剩呢
There's plenty of formula left.
我已經做好蔬菜泥了
I've pureed the veggies,
或者你也可以加一個香蕉
or you could mash a banana.
印度菜怎麼樣? 我可以給她一塊咖喱呢
And what about Indian food? I can give her a curry, can't I?
不  不  不  Dexter  不
No, no, no, Dexter. No.
Sylvie  我在開玩笑
Sylvie, I'm joking.
哦  我明白了
Oh, I see.
我一直惦掛着那些東西  不是嗎?
I keep missing those, don't I?
我很抱歉我來晚了
I'm sorry. It's just that I'm late.
我甚至不知道我爲什麼要去
I don't even know why I'm going.
-我太老了參加不了女生派對  -不   纔不是
-I'm too old for hen nights. -No, you're not.
我叫的出租車來了
That's my cab.
好的
Right, come on, then.
明天早上我會回來的
I'll be back tomorrow morning.
好的
Okay.
儘量不要把房子燒光
Be good. Try not to burn the house down.
我會沒事的 我會沒事的
I'll be fine. I'll be fine.
再見  跟媽媽說再見
Goodbye, my sweetheart. Say goodbye to Mummy.
跟媽媽說再見
Say goodbye to Mummy.
哦  我知道  親愛的我很抱歉
Oh, I know, honey. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
玩得開心點
Have a good time.
哦! 我們會好好的  對吧?
Oh! Come on. We'll be all right, won't we?
聚會開始了就沒有盡頭
Party started there's no end in sight
每個人都翩翩起舞
Everybody's moving to the rhythm that's inside
這是一個瘋狂的世界  但今晚卻很正常
It's a crazy world but tonight's the right situation
我是Spartacus
I am Spartacus.
不  我是Spartacus
No, I'm Spartacus.
我是Spartacus
I'm Spartacus.
Wahey! 讓我們給予他最熱烈的掌聲...
Wahey! Let's have a big hand and give a round of applause...
瞧  JAS  看  這是爸爸的前女友
Look, Jas. Look, that's Daddy's ex.
...籃球巨星 TJ 和 Mickey D!
...for basketball stars TJ and Mickey D!
她說話是不是很大聲嗎?
Isn't she loud?
你能讓他們都擠到鏡頭前嗎
Can you even fit them in a two-shot?
他們是如此高大   以至於我幾乎融化在這裏
They are so tall. I'm practically melting over here.
她是不是一個說話很響亮  很大聲的女孩?
Isn't she a loud, loud girl?
"Julie Criscoll  才15歲  覺得
"Julie Criscoll, aged 15, wanted
"沒有比改變世界更加重要的了
"nothing more than to change the world.
"如果所有的政客仔細的聆聽"
"If only all the politicians would actually listen."
呀  這就是 EM
Yeah, well that's Em.
是 EM 嗎?
Is that Em?
是啊  那是EM 是她寫了這本書
Yeah, that's Em. She wrote the book.
是我
It's me.
我很抱歉  親愛的
I'm so sorry, darling.
你看  聚會如何呢?  一切可好?
Look, how's the party going? How's it all going?
嗯...
Um...
我們全都要去俱樂部  她怎麼樣了?
We're all going on to some club. How is she?
睡着了   終於
Asleep. You know, finally.
這段時間她一直醒着?
She's been awake all this time?
是啊  我的錯  我應該給她脫咖啡因的
Yeah, my fault. I should have given her the decaf.
看到了嗎?  我讓你笑
See? There you go. I made you laugh.
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
是啊  不  不  我很好  我很好
Yeah. No, no, I'm good. I'm good.
爲什麼呢? 你是不是在擔心?
Why? Were you worried?
哦  不  嗯...
Oh, no. Um...
沒有理由   我只是...
No reason. I just...
好吧   我只是想確認一下你和...
Well, I was just checking up on you and...
好了  一切都很好
Well, everything's fine.
好吧
All right.
Sylvie Look, Sylvie,
我知道我不擅長這個  當爸爸和丈夫的事情
I know I'm not good at all this, you know, dad/husband thing.
你做得很好   Dexter
You're doing fine, Dexter.
不  我知道如果你有一份收入
No, and I know if you had a receipt,
你會帶我回到很久以前
you would have taken me back a long time ago.
但是 我正在解決好嗎?  耐心等一下吧
But, you know, I'm working on it, all right? So bear with me. That's all.
我要掛電話了
I've got to go.
明天見
I'll see you tomorrow. All right.
再見  晚安
Night. Good night.
好笑嗎?
Funny?
非常有趣
Very funny.
看看你  你甚至看起來像一個作家
Well, look at you. You even look like a writer.
一個在巴黎的作家
A writer in Paris.
是不是有一個詞專門形容這個的?
There's a word for this, isn't there?
嗯  Butch
Uh, butch.
我本來想說 gamine
I was gonna say gamine.
你看起來又是什麼樣子?
What do you look like?
我?  一個搞砸了的離婚者
Me? A screwed-up divorce?
我的公寓就在不遠處?我們可以...
So my apartment's not far. Shall we?
你會留在這裏多久?
How long are you staying for?
我想這由你決定  真的...
I suppose it's up to you, really. It's just...
我只是想說點什麼
Look, I just wanted to say something
說一些在電話裏說不出口的事
which I couldn't really do over the phone.
好了  自從我們最後一次在倫敦見面以來...
Well, ever since we were last together in London...
Dexter  你說別的之前  我...
Dexter, before you say anything else, I have to...
有些事情我要告訴你
There's something I have to tell you.
你去約會了!
You've met someone!
這很難以置信嗎?
Is that really so hard to believe?
-一個人嗎? -是的  一個人 一個傢伙
-A man? -Yes, a man. A guy.
一個傢伙! 他現在是男人了是吧? 我懂了
A guy! He's a guy now, is he? I see.
他叫 Jean-Pierre
He's called Jean-Pierre,
Jean-Pierre Dusollier  Jean-Pierre Dusollier.
什麼  他是法國人嗎?
What, he's French?
不  Dex  他是威爾士人
No, Dex, he's Welsh.
他的帥氣  他的迷人
He's handsome. He's charming.
他只是非常  非常法國
He's just very, very French.
什麼  你的意思是粗魯?
What, you mean rude?
不  囂張?
No. Arrogant?
抽菸太多了  戴着一串洋蔥
Smokes too much, wears a string of onions.
你爲什麼要這樣?
Why are you being like this?
哦  你的意思是性感嗎?
Oh, God, you mean sexy. Is that what you mean?
你在跟很多人內個?
You're having lots of sex?
從什麼時候開始我需要徵求你的許可?
Since when do I need to ask your permission?
誰會知道啊  你從來也不徵求我的許可
God knows you never asked mine.
但我們只是睡在一起
But we just slept together.
我沒有忘記
I haven't forgotten.
Dexter  我們有點醉了
Dexter, we got a bit drunk.
是啊  但沒那麼喝醉了
Yeah, not that drunk.
你把你的褲子脫了放在你的鞋子上
You took your trousers off over your shoes.
不  我沒有
No, I didn't.
我有嗎?
Did I?
我以爲你在爲Sylvie和離婚的事煩惱
I think that you were upset about Sylvie and the divorce,
而你需要在一個肩膀上哭
and you needed a shoulder to cry on.
或者睡在那上面
Or sleep with.
而這就是我  陪睡小姐
And that's what I was, a shoulder to sleep with.
這就是你這樣做的原因對吧?
And that's why you did it, was it?
爲了讓我精神振奮起來
To cheer me up.
反正這奏效了
Well, it worked, didn't it?
那是我生命中最美好的夜晚之一
If you must know, it was one of the better nights of my life.
看到了嗎?
See?
表醬紫
Don't fish.
Dex   只有一次
Dex, it was one time.
纔不是  三次了
Well, it was three times.
來吧  你看  你不覺得這是一個好主意?
Come on. Look, you don't think it's a good idea?
你和我兩個人在一起
You and me.
是啊  我一直這麼認爲
I do. I did.
在80年代後期
In the late '80s.
對
Right.
最好動身了
Better get going.
爲什麼呢? 我們要做什麼呢?
Why? What are we doing?
Jean-Pierre 想見你
Jean-Pierre wants to meet you.
哦  你在開玩笑
Oh, you're kidding.
我們要聽他彈奏
We're going to hear him play.
彈奏?
Play?
他是爵士樂音樂家
He's a jazz musician.
壞小子
Bastard.
我們要聽他用鋼琴彈上九個小時爵士樂
We're going to listen to him play free jazz on the piano for about nine hours,
會很有樂趣的 根本不會尷尬
and it's going to be lots of fun and in no way awkward.
你不是要這樣走出去吧?
You're not going out like that, are you?
別廢話了
Just do me up.
那就是 Jean-Pierre
That's Jean-Pierre.
哪個?
Where?
噢   你至少可以找一個好看點的
Oh, God. You could have at least found someone a bit good-looking.
你知道  EM  我敢肯定他是一個
You know, Em, I'm sure he's a
很好的爵士樂鋼琴家
fine jazz pianist.
我只是不確定我可以這樣做
I just don't think I can do this.
哦 真的嗎?
Oh. Really?
是啊  我想我還是是去看電影   然後回公寓
Yeah, I'll just go and see a movie and go back to the apartment.
然後我想我要去搭明天第一趟火車回去
And then I think I'm going to get the first train back tomorrow.
你不一定要離開
You don't have to leave.
我覺得我要
I think I do.
對不起  Dex
I'm sorry, Dex.
嘿  不要這樣
Hey, don't be.
去吧
Go on.
嘿  你好
Hey. Salut
等等!  Dexter !
Wait! Dexter!
我以爲我已經不在意你了
I thought I got rid of you.
如果你耍弄我  Dexter ...
If you muck me about, Dexter...
EM  我發誓 我發誓  我不會
Em, I swear. I swear I won't.
引誘我  或者讓我失望  或着暗算我
Lead me on, or let me down, or go behind my back,
我會殺死你的
I will murder you.
我不會這樣做
I won't do that.
你發誓?
You swear?
是的  我發誓 我發誓
Yeah, I swear. I swear.
我想感謝大家百忙中抽空來我們的婚禮
I would like to thank everyone for coming to our wedding.
這隻能形容爲旋風式的浪漫
For what can only be described as a whirlwind romance.
笑聲停止
Pause for laughter.
說真的  當人們問Emma和我第一次是怎麼遇見的
Seriously, when people ask how Emma and I first met,
我就告訴他們我們一起長大
I tell them that we grew up together.
Blah, blah, blah. Blah, blah, blah. Blah, blah, blah. Blah, blah, blah.
你不會說內個的那一天吧?
You're not going to say, "Blah, blah, blah," on the day, are you?
你不應該聽到這個的
You are not supposed to be hearing this.
如果我有注意到怎麼辦?
What if I have notes?
來吧  讓我看看
Come on, let me see.
不要
No, no.
當我們結婚的時候  你要絕對服從我
When we're married, you're going to have to obey me.
是的  我敢肯定這將要發生
Yeah, I'm sure that's going to happen.
什麼? 不是嗎?
What? Not again?
你介意嗎?
You don't mind, do you?
不  我不介意
No, I don't mind.
雖然有健康和安全問題
Although, there are health and safety issues.
我可能會失去我的駕照的
I could lose my license.
他們肯定不知道我們去哪裏了
They'll wonder where we've got to.
MMM!  Mmm! Mmm.
我可以肯定的這是燒焦的味道
I can definitely smell burning.
你好
Hello, hello.
嗨
Hi, there.
來這裏  我們走吧
Come here, you. Here we go.
你想給我一個吻嗎? 親我吧
Do you want to give me a big kiss? Give me a big kiss.
繼續
Go on.
看電視只能從5:30看到6:00
TV between 5:30 and 6:00, but no more.
而她7點半一定要上牀
And she has to be in bed by 7:30.
好  你想跑進去?
All right, do you want to run inside?
去看看 Emma  好女孩
Go see Emma. Good girl.
我在這裏  Jasmine
I'm out here, Jasmine.
她現在很喜歡來這裏
She's loving coming here at the moment.
好  很好  非常好
Well, good. That's great.
我真爲你高興
I'm really pleased for you.
我會邀請你進來 這...
Look, I'd invite you in. It's just...
不  沒事  我們要去看看我的家人了
No, it's fine. We've got to go and see my family.
玩得開心點  謝謝
Have fun. Thanks.
-Dexter?  - 怎麼了
-Dexter?  -Yeah.
我一直在想一件事
I've been thinking.
我也有
So have I.
我想與我愛的男人要一個孩子
I want a child with the man I love.
如果他不想要孩子  那我和你生一個吧
And if he won't do it, then I want one with you.
好吧  那我們最好現在開始
Well, then, we'd better get started.
我看上去真疲憊
I look so tired.
所以纔要多鍛鍊  遲點來跟我游泳吧
So take some exercise. Come swimming with me later.
不  不  我不能 我在咖啡館有太多事忙了
No, no, I can't. I've got to do too much at the cafe.
好 不要
Fine. Don't.
順便說一下  我知道你很八卦
By the way, in case you're interested,
事實上我沒有懷孕
I'm not pregnant.
EM  你怎麼知道?
Em, how do you know?
你怎麼想的?
How do you think?
但我們可以再試一次
We could try again, though.
來吧  看着... 不  不  不  不 來吧
Come on, look... No, no, no, no. Come on.
我很抱歉  好嗎?
Look, I'm sorry. All right?
不  我沒有怪你
No, I am for taking it out on you.
我們一直狀態不佳?
We're not at our best today, are we?
聽着  要不我們下班後見面吧?
Listen, why don't we meet each other after work?
然後去電影院看電影  你挑電影吧
We'll go to the movies. Your choice.
看有字幕的
Something with subtitles.
哦
Ooh.
然後我們可以去吃晚餐  就你和我
And we can go and have some dinner. Just you and me,
再然後我們就解決這個問題  好嗎?
and we can work this out. All right?
-我保證 -Mmm-hmm.
-I promise.  -MMM - HMM
是啊
Yeah.
好了
Okay.
謝謝 非常感謝
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
嘿   我只是想說我可能要遲到了
Hey, there. Just to say I'm running late,
不過我已經快到了
but I'm on my way.
我很抱歉今天上午這麼生氣
I'm sorry for being so snappy this morning.
嘿   我只是想說我可能要遲到了
Hey, there. Just to say I'm running late,
不過我已經快到了
but I'm on my way.
我很抱歉今天上午這麼生氣
And I'm sorry for being so snappy this morning.
我只想說你是一個好人
I just wanted to say you're a fine thing,
Dexter Mayhew Dexter Mayhew.
我十分愛你
I love you very much.
好吧  笑吧你  你真幸運!
Okay, there you go. Lucky you!
爸爸
Dad.
- Dexter ? 你好  親愛的
- Dexter ? Hello, darling.
你沒事吧? 去穿衣服
Are you all right? Go and get dressed.
Sylvie, Sylvie,
Dexter? Dexter ? Sylvie, Sylvie.
Dexter? Dexter ?
Sylvie  Sylvie  我搞砸了
Sylvie, Sylvie, I screwed up.
Jasmine  現在就去!
Jasmine, now!
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
沒事  你沒有
It's all right. You're all right.
不  我搞砸了
No, I screwed up.
來吧  起來吧
Come on, let's get you up. Come on.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
好
It's all right.
噢   Dex   來吧
Aw, Dex, come on.
你這個可憐的東西
You poor thing.
噢  上帝  Dexter
Oh, God. Dexter.
- 由於今日連續降雨 水位開始回升
-As the rain came down,the water levels began to rise.
那麼這將是一個一年一度的節日  你覺得呢?
So is this going to be an annual festival, do you think?
每年7月15日?
Every year, 15th of July?
好吧  我希望不會
Well, I hope not.
我不想  談心
I don't want a heart-to-heart.
你呢?
Do you?
不  我寧可不談
No, no. I'd rather not.
只是說  我覺得你應該做的最好的事
Except to say, that I think the best thing that you could do
就是像 Emma 還在你身邊那樣繼續生活下去
would be to try to live your life as if Emma was still here.
不是嗎?
Don't you?
我不知道我能不能
I don't know if I can.
當然你也可以
Of course you can.
你覺得我最近10年都做了什麼?
What do you think I've been doing for the past 10 years?
現在是9點 Silent Witness 要開始了
Now Silent Witness is on. 9:00.
對
Right.
Ian 上帝!
Ian. God!
嗨 你好
Hi. Hello, mate.
你呢? 是啊  看看這個
Are you well? Yeah, look at this.
所以  你最近怎樣?  脫口秀怎麼樣?
So, how are you? How's the stand-up comedy?
我放棄那個了
Oh, well, I gave that up, actually.
這真可惜
That's a shame.
不  因爲我從來都不擅長這個
No, not really, because I was never any good.
我唯一的一次讓 Emma 笑
The only time I ever made Emma laugh
就是當我從樓梯掉下去的時候
was when I fell down the stairs. Really.
不  我現在賣保險
No, I'm in insurance now.
太好了
Great, great.
我討厭今天 七月十五月
I hate today. Fifteenth of July.
聖斯威遜節
Saint Swithin's Day.
這是一個艱難的聖斯威遜節
It's a tough one.
我以前從來沒有注意過它
I never noticed it before,
但它是總是在那裏靜靜守候
but it was always there just waiting,
潛伏
lurking.
我以前也很恨你
I used to hate you, too.
很暴力  Dexter
Quite violently, actually, Dexter.
我很抱歉  但...
No, I'm sorry, but...
因爲  她點燃了你的激情
Because, she lit up with you.
她從來沒有這樣對我
Just in a way that she never would with me,
這件事一直讓我很生氣  因爲...
and it used to make me so angry because...
我覺得你不配得到她  我可以這樣說嗎?
I didn't think that you deserved her. Can I say this?
是啊  繼續
Yeah, go on.
她讓你體面
She made you decent.
然後爲了回報  你讓她非常高興
And then in return, you made her so happy.
太高興了
So happy.
爲此我一直很感激你的
And I will always be grateful to you for that.
就因爲這件事  我曾經跟她吵過架
And on that bombshell,  back to the sticks.
看看我的宿命  看他們
There's my lot out there. Oh! Look at them.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
好吧   保持聯繫  我會給你打個電話
So, listen, we'll stay in touch. I'll give you a call.
不  我不認爲這是必要的
No, I don't think that's necessary.
我覺得我們以後不會再聯繫了
I think we're done here.
來這裏
Come here.
祝你好運
Good luck, mate. All right?
你也一樣
You, too.
謝謝
Thank you.
你的到處都是蛋糕碎
You've got cake everywhere.
起來
Wake up.
起牀啦
好 不要驚慌  就我一個
It's all right. Don't panic. It's only me.
Emma  Emma Morley Emma. Emma Morley.
是的 你好
Yes. Hello.
你有什麼建議呢?
So what do you suggest we do?
我們可以保持聯繫
We could stay in touch.
今天  我們是註定要做一些東西的
Today. We're meant to be doing something today.
對  對   對
Right. Right, right.
你看  今天對我來說真的有點棘手
Look, today's a bit tricky for me, really.
不  不  不是  這只是...
No, no, it's not that. It's just...
好吧  我要去見我的父母
Well, I'm meeting my parents,
然後我得回來...
and then I've got to get back...
哦  對的  你或許應該去
Oh, yeah, yeah, you should probably go then.
能遇見你真好 再見了
It was lovely to meet you. Bye, now.
我遲點纔要去見他們  所以如果你想
Look, that's not until later, so if you wanted to,
我們可以去散步嗎?
we could go for a walk or something?
好啊
Okay.
來吧  跟上
Come on, keep up.
是這些鞋子的原因 我不能穿着這種鞋爬山
It's these shoes. I can't mountain climb in brogues.
這不是喬戈裏峯
It's not K2.
這只是一座大山  好吧?
It's just a big hill, all right?
小孩子都能爬上去
A child could do it.
我不希望你想起昨晚的任何事
I don't want you thinking I'm bothered or anything about last night.
我不希望要你的電話號碼
I don't want your phone number,
或者信件 或者明信片
or letters, or postcards.
我不想跟你結婚
I don't want to get married to you.
也絕對不希望懷上你的孩子
Definitely don't want to have your babies.
不管明天發生什麼事  把握好今天
Whatever happens tomorrow, we've had today.
如果我們將來偶然相遇
And if we should bump into each other sometime in the future,
那也很好啊
well, that's fine, too.
我們會成爲朋友
We'll be friends.
是啊
Yeah, right.
或者   另一方面...
Or, you know, on the other hand...
繼續
Go on.
好吧  我的父母暫時還不會回來
Well, my parents don't arrive until later.
所以?
So?
所以  我家裏沒有人了
So, well, the flat's empty.
如果你想完成我們之間未了的事
You know, if you wanted to finish what we started.
什麼? 內個?
What? Sober?
而且是在白天
And in daylight.
看誰快!
Race you!
你想要我揹你嗎 老頭?
Do you want a piggy-back, you old man?
這鞋子 在這裏根本走不動
It's these shoes. There's no blooming grip on these things.
這裏  來這裏
Here, come here, you.
你帶 Emma 來過這裏?
Did you come up here with Emma?
是的  一次
Yeah, once.
這是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago now.
你想念她嗎?
Do you miss her?
嗯  我當然想念她
Well, of course, I do.
她... 她是我最好的的朋友
She was... She was my best friend.
現在誰是你最好的朋友呢?
Who's your best friend now then?
當然是你   來
Well, you are, of course. Come here.
那  誰是你最好的朋友?
Well, who's yours?
我認爲可能是媽媽
I think it's probably Mum.
是啊
Yeah.
我不是那麼吧可怕?
I'm not so terrible though, am I?
我纔不會回答你
I'm not answering that.
你知道你是什麼
You know what you are.
轉過這個彎就是了 這邊走
It's just round the corner. This way.
Dexter ! Oh, Dexter!
可惡  他們早到了
Damn it, they're early.
你們真早
You're early.
我們以爲我們會令你感到驚訝
We thought we'd surprise you.
顯然  得逞了
Clearly, we have.
媽媽  爸爸  這是 Emma Morley
Mum, Dad, this is Emma Morley. Morley.
你好  很高興見到你
Hello. Pleased to meet you.
Emma  你會和我們一起喝茶 是嗎?
Emma, you'll join us for tea, yes?
不  不  謝謝  我應該讓你去喝茶的
No, no, thanks. I should leave you to it.
-你要走了嗎? -是啊
-Are you going to go? -Yeah. Well,
很高興可以和你見面...
pleasure to meet you and...
祝你幸福
Well, have a nice life.
好了
Okay.
我很抱歉  我們剛剛打攪你了嗎?
I'm sorry. Did we just interrupt something?
沒有  Emma  只是我的好朋友
No, no. Emma's just a good friend.
昨天你不也穿着這件嗎?
Weren't you wearing this yesterday?
流氓
The rascal.
EM  等一下
Em, wait! Wait, wait.
我需要你的電話號碼
Look, I need your phone number.
我的電話號碼?  當然
My number? Right. Of course.
我對這一切感到很抱歉
Look, I'm so sorry about all of that.
我沒想見到他們直到我們... 你懂的
I wasn't expecting them until after we... Well, you know.
對
Right.
這是我在愛丁堡的電話
This is me in Edinburgh.
對
Right.
我父母的電話
My parents' number
還有他們的地址   以防萬一
and their address just in case.
對
Right.
爸爸工作的地方有傳真機
Oh. Dad's got a fax machine at work.
留個電話號碼就夠了
Just the phone number's fine.
謝謝
Thank you.
我要走了
Look, I've got to go.
我知道
I know.
但我們會再見面的
But we will see each other again.
我知道我們會
I know we will.
再見了   Dex
Goodbye, Dex.
再見
Goodbye.